Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/john-canty-4b255ba (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Banking
Asset Management
Portfolio Management

Languages

Spanish

John Canty

SVP-Senior Relationship Manager, Middle Market Commercial Banking Group at Wells Fargo

Birmingham, Alabama

Summary

Experienced and energetic 22-year corporate banking veteran with broad product knowledgeable across Capital Markets, Corporate Finance, Treasury Management, and Asset Management fields, Proven credentials for building, maintaining, and uptiering a portfolio of clients, prospecting new clients, geographic business expansion and execution of new business strategies. Deep understanding of credit, corporate finance and capital markets applied to a broad spectrum of industries. Extensive client experience in Southeast and Midwest US middle-market and large-corporate segments.

Experience

Wells Fargo

SVP-Senior Relationship Manager, Middle Market Commercial Banking Group

2019 - Present (1 year)

Birmingham, Alabama Area

Responsible for client relationship management/coverage, new-business development, prospecting, and cross-selling solutions with a team of bankers covering Southeastern US. Capabilities include Corporate Finance, Treasury Management, Trade Finance, Capital Markets, and other strengths.

Northern Trust Corporation

16 years

SVP-Corporate Banking SRM and OCIO Practice Lead June 2015 - 2018 (3 years)

Greater Chicago Area

Lead Corporate Banking Relationship Manager handling portfolio of 31 corporate middle-market and large-corporate clients in Midwest and Southeast US. Exceeded performance goals by 61% in 2016, 26% in 2017, and 42% in 2018. Led roll-out of Project Accelerate, Northern Trust's effort to jumpstart OCIO sales in medium-to-small DB plans; responsible for two OCIO wins.

Senior Vice President-Division Manager August 2007 - June 2015 (7 years 11 months)

Managed a group of bankers and analysts in de novo Division focused on large corporate (\$500MM+) clients in Midwest and Southeast US. Via block-tackle prospecting, team expanded client portfolio from 36 to 95, lifting revenues from \$31MM to \$72MM, boosting Division from #5 to #1 revenue generator, and achieving 76% cross-sell rate. Coached junior cadre staff. Managed through 3 distressed credit situations with \$0 in loan losses. Promoted team ethos that led to 26 new Investment Management mandates, 16 Master Trust relationships, 8 Treasury management wins, and 6 Outsourced Chief Investment Officer engagements. Co-led successful Energy Lending project.

Vice President - Corporate Banking, Middle Market Client Group August 2002 - July 2007 (5 years)

Responsible for client coverage, business-development, cross-selling, and prospecting activities across a portfolio of middle-market clients in Southeastern and Midwestern US.

Wachovia Vice President-US Corporate Banking 1996 - 2002 (6 years)

Education

Duke University - The Fuqua School of Business MBA, Accounting and Finance (1994 - 1996)

Williams College Bachelor's Degree, History (1984 - 1988)

Phillips Academy High School · (1980 - 1984)

Lake Forest Country Day